{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Virulence trait of Agrobacterium tumefaciens is borne on", "opta": "chromosomal DNA", "optb": "tumour inducing plasmid DNA", "optc": "both chromosomal and plasmid DNA", "optd": "cryptic plasmid DNA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The size of the virulent plasmid of Agrobacterium tumefaciens is", "opta": "40-80 kb", "optb": "80-120 kb", "optc": "140-235 kb", "optd": ">235 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true about the helper plasmids?", "opta": "These can replicate in Agrobacterium", "optb": "These help in the mediating conjugation of intermediate vectors", "optc": "These can't replicate in Agrobacterium", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which technique is used to introduce genes into dicots?", "opta": "electroporation", "optb": "particle acceleration", "optc": "microinjection", "optd": "Ti plasmid infection", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Direct DNA uptake by protoplasts can be stimulated by", "opta": "polyethylene glycol (PEG)", "optb": "decanal", "optc": "luciferin", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a plant tumour cell", "opta": "complete Ti plasmid is incorporated in plant nuclear DNA", "optb": "different parts of the Ti-plasmid are incorporated", "optc": "only a small specific segment of callus T DNA is incorporated", "optd": "may vary from plant to plant", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Co-integrating transformation vectors must include a region of homology in", "opta": "the vector plasmid", "optb": "the Ti-plasmid", "optc": "between vector plasmid and Ti-plasmid", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Crown gall tissue", "opta": "can be cultivated in vitro in absence of bacteria", "optb": "retains tumorous properties when cultivated", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "shows tumorous properties only in presence of bacteria", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Integrated nopaline T-DNA occurs as", "opta": "single segment", "optb": "two segments", "optc": "three segments", "optd": "four segments", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Opines are", "opta": "amino acid derivatives found in tumor tissues", "optb": "amino acid derivatives found in normal tissues", "optc": "amino acid derivatives found in both normal as well as tumor tissues", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true about Agrobacterium tumefaciens?", "opta": "It causes crown gall disease of plants", "optb": "It infects gymosperms", "optc": "It infects dicotyledonous angiosperms", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the liposome mediated gene transfer in plants, nucleic acids are", "opta": "protected from nuclease digestion", "optb": "stable in liposomes", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "not stable in liposomes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Advantage of microprojectile method over microinjection method for gene transfer in plants include", "opta": "intact cells are used", "optb": "method is universal in its application irrespective of all shape, size, type and presence or absence of cell wall", "optc": "gene can be transferred to many cells simultaneously", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "On Ti-plasmid T-region or T-DNA is flanked by a direct repeat of", "opta": "12 bp", "optb": "20 bp", "optc": "25 bp", "optd": "30 bp", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agrobacterium tumefaciens is a", "opta": "gram (+) bacteria", "optb": "gram (-) bacteria", "optc": "a fungi", "optd": "a yeast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microprojectile method of gene transfer in plants involves delivery of DNA", "opta": "with the help of micromanipulator", "optb": "with the help of bolistics", "optc": "with the help of needles", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following genes are constitutively expressed and control the plant induced activation of other vir genes?", "opta": "vir A and vir G", "optb": "vir C and vir D", "optc": "vir B and vir E", "optd": "vir A and vir B", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Integrated octopine T DNA occurs as", "opta": "single segment", "optb": "two segments", "optc": "three segments", "optd": "four segments", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Liposomes mediated gene transfer in plants involves", "opta": "plasmid DNA enclosed in a lipid bag", "optb": "fusion of liposomes with protoplast", "optc": "use of polyethylene glycol (PEG)", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following plant signal molecules regulate the expression of vir B, C, D and E in case of tobacco?", "opta": "Acetosyringone", "optb": "\u03b1-hydroxy syringone", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Opines that are present in crown gall tumour include", "opta": "octopine", "optb": "nopaline", "optc": "agropine", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Intermediate vectors containing T-DNA are conjugation deficient. Thus conjugation is mediated in presence of which of the following plasmid?", "opta": "pRK 2013", "optb": "pRN 3", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true about T DNA?", "opta": "Integration of T DNA can occur at many different, apparently random, sites in the plant nuclear DNA", "optb": "Integration of T DNA occurs only at one specific sites in the plant nuclear DNA", "optc": "Integration of T DNA occurs at two specific sites in the plant nuclear DNA", "optd": "Integration of T DNA occurs at one site that may be random in the plant nuclear DNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true about the direct repeats flanking T-DNA?", "opta": "They are conserved between nopaline and octopine Ti-plasmids", "optb": "These repeats are transferred intact to the plant genome", "optc": "These are important in integration mechanism", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The left segment of octopine T-DNA (TL) is necessary for", "opta": "enzymes for agropine biosynthesis", "optb": "tumour formation", "optc": "conjugative transfer", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true for microinjection technique that involves transfer of DNA into protoplast?", "opta": "It is carried out with the help of micromanipulator", "optb": "The recipient cells are immobilized on artificial support or artificially bound to substarate", "optc": "It employs needle with diameter greater than cell diameter", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The right segment of octopine T-DNA (TR) is necessary for", "opta": "enzymes for agropine biosynthesis", "optb": "tumour formation", "optc": "conjugative transfer", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Opine synthesis is the property", "opta": "conferred to plant cells when it transformed by Agrobacterium tumefaciens", "optb": "determined by the bacteria Agrobacterium tumefaciens", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "of normal plant cells", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Virulent strains of Agrobacterium contain large Ti-plasmids, which are responsible for the DNA transfer and subsequent disease symptoms. It has been shown that Ti-plasmids contain", "opta": "one set of sequence necessary for gene transfer", "optb": "two sets of sequence necessary for gene transfer", "optc": "three sets of sequence necessary for gene transfer", "optd": "four sets of sequence necessary for gene transfer", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The direct repeats flanking the T-DNA of Agrobacterium tume-faciens are known as", "opta": "cos site", "optb": "flanking sequences", "optc": "border sequences", "optd": "transfer sequences", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "T-DNA transfer and processing into plant genome requires products of which of the following genes?", "opta": "vir A,B", "optb": "vir G,C", "optc": "vir D,E", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Because of large size of Ti-plasmid, intermediate vectors (IV) are developed in which T DNA has been subcloned into", "opta": "pBR 322 based plasmid vector", "optb": "pRK 2013", "optc": "pRN 3", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The transfer of intermediate vectors into Agrobacterium are brought about by", "opta": "transformation", "optb": "biparental mating", "optc": "triparental mating", "optd": "transduction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In response to the activating signal molecule, an endonuclease is produced that causes nicks in the T-DNA. It is encoded by", "opta": "vir A", "optb": "vir B", "optc": "vir C", "optd": "vir D", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microinjection involves", "opta": "injection of large amount of DNA", "optb": "injection of DNA into bigger cells", "optc": "injection with needle having diameter greater than cell diameter", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following are used as selection marker for the cells transformed with Agrobacterium?", "opta": "Neomycin phosphotransferase", "optb": "Streptomycin phosphotransferase", "optc": "Hygromycin phosphotransferase", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vir genes required for the T-DNA transfer and processing are located", "opta": "on the T-DNA", "optb": "outside the T-DNA region", "optc": "on the plant genome", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plant transformation vectors based on Agrobacterium can generally be divided into", "opta": "two vectors", "optb": "four vectors", "optc": "six vectors", "optd": "eight vectors", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}